A Guide to the Records of First Lady, 2014-2017
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of First Lady, 2014-2017
The Library of Virginia
52180
XX cubic feet (XX Boxes)
Virginia First Lady
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 52180 transferred from the Office of the First Lady on January 12, 2018.
Historical Information
XX
Scope and Content
records consist of 19 archival boxes and are divided into 4 series. Series have been designated for Correspondence (I), Initiatives (II), Scheduling Office (III), and Subject files (IV). These records document the work of the First Lady during the McAuliffe administration and were created or collected, 2014-2017, though some documents in this collection pre-date this time period.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence, 2014-2017
Series II. Initiatives, 2014-2017
Series III. Scheduling, 2014-2017
Series IV. Subject files, 2014-2017.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 2014-2017., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  The vast majority of the correspondence in this series is comprised of thank you notes to the First Lady for her appearance at events or involvment in projects.
  - Correspondence, 2014 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2014 May. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2014 June. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2014 July. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Sept. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2014 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 2015 May. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2015 June. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2015 July. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2015 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (no month), 2015. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2016 May. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2016 June. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2016 July. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2016 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (no month), 2016. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2017 May. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2017 June. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2017 July. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Aug. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2017 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (no month), 2017. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (no date), 2014-2017. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series II. Initiatives, 2014-2017., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 5-13)
  Initiatives, 2014-2017, are housed in 9 archival boxes and organized into 3 subseries for: I. Transportation legislation and funding, 2006-2007; II. Transportation Bill (HB 3202), 2007; and III. Transportation Special Session, 2008. This series focuses on Governor Kaine's transportation priorities and plans, funding and projects. Includes correspondence, budgets, legislation, draft legislation, presentations, reports, revenue data, statistical analyses, summaries, and talking points.
  - Nutrition, 2014-2017.
    XX
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 2015-2017. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Breakfast After the Bell, 2016. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Briefing memos, 2014. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP) - At-Risk After School Meals Program, 2015-2016. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP) - Campaign / Food Research Action Center, 2016. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP) - Outreach, 2016-2017. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP) - Stakeholders, 2015-2016. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP) - Summit, 2016 June 9. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Child Care Resources - Nourishing the Future Press kit, 2016. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Child Nutrition Reauthorization bill, 2015-2016. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - City-School Partnership Model for Challenged Schools, 2015. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide, 2014. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide, 2015. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide, 2016-2017. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide - Ending Child Hunger Workgroup, 2015-2017. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide - Meeting, 2015 Feb 4. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide - Meeting, 2016 June 3. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide - Strategic Planning, undated. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide - Website, 2015-2016. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Community Eligibility Provision, 2014. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Community Eligiblity Provision - Making High Poverty Schools Hunger Free, 2014. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Congressional Testimony - House Education and Workforce Committee, 2015 Apr 15. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Consolidation - Summer Food Service Program / Child and Adult Care Food Program, 2017. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Education, State Board of, 2015. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Education, Dept. of - School breakfast, 2015-2017. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - End Childhood Hunger Demonstration Project, 2014. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - End Childhood Hunger Demonstration Project - Virginia Project 365 to End Childhood Hunger, 2014-2015. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - End Childhood Hunger Demonstration Project - Virginia Project 365 to End Childhood Hunger, 2016 Jan-Aug. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - End Childhood Hunger Demonstration Project - Virginia Project 365 to End Childhood Hunger, 2016 Sept-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - End Childhood Hunger Demonstration Project - Virginia Project 365 to End Childhood Hunger, 2017. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Faith-Based Partnerships to End Child Hunger (Bishop Mauney), 2015-2016. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Farm to School Program, 2013. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Farmers Markets, 2014. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Food Access (notes), 2014. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Food and Beverage, 2014. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Food and Farm End Hunger Workshop, 2017. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Food Banks, 2014. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Food Corps, 2017. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Food Crop Donation Tax Credit, 2017. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Food Deserts in Virginia, 2014. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Foundation for Healthy Youth, Virginia, 2014-2016. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Grocery Investment Fund - Virginia Healthy Food Financing Plan, 2015. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Grow NYC, undated. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Health, Dept. of, 2014-2017. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Healthy Base Initiative, undated. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Hunger Free Community Network - Agenda, 2014 Mar 1. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - No Kid Hungry - Breakfast Changes Lives, 2013. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - No Kid Hungry - Gubernatorial Briefing Book, 2017. (Box 8)
    - No Kid Hungry - NGA Learning Lab on Strategies to Reduce Childhood Hunger, 2017 June 12-13. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - No Kid Hungry - Starts with Breakfast, undated. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Northern Virginia Family Service / Prince William County Food Council, 2015. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Northern Virginia Partnerships, 2016. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Nutrition - Notes and miscellaneous, 2014-2017. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Nutrition Program Briefing for the First Lady, 2014 Mar 5. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nutritional Program Consolidation, 2015-2016. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Out-of-School Nutrition Summit, 2015 Dec 11. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Partnership to End Childhood Hunger Summit: Outreach to Faith-Based Leaders, 2010 Nov 8. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Regulations, 2014. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - RVA Food Collaboration, 2016. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - School Breakfast Challenge, 2015-2016. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - School Breakfast Programs, 2015-2016. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - School Breakfast Service Models, 2016-2017. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - School Breakfast Summit, 2015 June 9. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - School Meal Access in Virginia, 2014. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - School Nutrition Association of Virginia, 2015; undated. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - School Nutrition Program, 2015. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 2015-2017. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Summer Programs, 2015. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), 2014. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) / Electronic Benefits Transfer (EBT), 2014. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Tax Credit for Food Bank Donations by Farmers, 2014. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Title I and Community Eligibility Provision, 2014-2017. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - United Way, 2015. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Broadcasters Association, 2014-2016. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University Brand Center, 2017. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Cooperative Extension - Reaching Limited Populations with Nutrition Education, 2014. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Early Childhood Foundation - Smart Beginnings, 2016. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Food Access Network (VFAN), 2017. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Food Access Network (VFAN), undated. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Food Access Network (VFAN) - Branding, undated. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Food System Council, 2014. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Grocery Investment Fund, 2015-2016. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Hunger Solutions Policy Conference, 2015 Oct 20. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Lutherans - Childhood Hunger Task Force, 2014 Dec 2. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Municipal League, 2016. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Specialty Crop Board, 2014. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Wholesome - Fresh Market Match, 2016-2017. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Children's Cabinet, 2014-2017.
    - Children's Cabinet, 2014-2015. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Children's Cabinet, 2016-2017. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Children's Cabinet, 2017. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Executive Mansion, 2015.
    - Acessibility enhancements, 2015. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Council on the Interstate Compact on Educational Opportunities for Military Children, 2014-2017.
    - General, 2014. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - General 2014. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - General, 2014-2015. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - General, 2015-2017. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Binder, 2014. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Briefing, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Connected students, 2017 Feb 8. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Council meeting, 2014 Apr 29. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Council meeting, 2014 Sept 15. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Council meeting, 2014 Dec 2. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Council meeting, 2015 Apr 2. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Council meeting, 2015 Sept 29. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Council meeting, 2016 May 23. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Council meeting, 2016 Dec 19. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Council meeting, 2017 June 7. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Council meeting, 2017 Oct 31. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Council meeting, 2017 Dec 4. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - National Guard, undated. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Students and families, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National Service, 2014-2017.
    - General, 2015-2016. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Americorps, 2015-2016. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Day of Service, 2014. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Employers of National Service - Press conference, 2015 Jan 27. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Franklin Project, undated. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Governor's Higher Education Summit on National Service (VMI), undated. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Millenial Civic Engagement Task Force, 2017. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Summit at JMU: Advancing Virginia's Commitment to Service, 2016 Feb 9. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Physical Evidence Recovery Kit (PERK), 2014-2017.
    - Evidence testing, 2014-2017. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Evidence testing, 2016. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Work Group meeting 2015 Nov 9. (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Series III. Scheduling, 2014-2017., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 14-15)
  - Add to calendar, 2015 June-July. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Event programs and invitations, 2016-2017. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Event: White House Summit on Working Families, 2014 June 11. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Event: London Trade Mission, 2014 July 12-16. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Event: Wolf Trap Ball, 2014 Sept 13. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Event: Voices of Survival, 2015 Jan 27. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Event: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Paris, 2015 Jan 27. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Event: OxFam, 2015 Nov. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Event: SPCA Fur Ball, 2015 Nov 7. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Event: Vice Presidential Debate, 2016 Oct 4. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Event: Richmond Police Memorial Relocation and Appreciation Ceremony, 2016 Oct 22. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Event: Boys and Girls Club Virginia Alliance - Day at the Capitol, 2017 Feb 2. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Event: Education Symposium, 2017 Mar 23. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Event: Loudoun County, 2017 May 20. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Event: Chesterfield County, 2017 June 14. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Event: Women's Global Leadership Forum, 2017 Nov 13. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Event: Give Kids a Smile, undated. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Invitations, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Invitations, 2015. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 2016. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 2016. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 2017. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, undated. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Subject files, 2014-2017., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 14-15)
  - Booker T. Washington High School Student Care Center, 2015 Oct 28. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Budget amendment - Notes, undated. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Budget and Policy Priorities - Office of the First Lady, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Capitol Square in the Civil War, undated. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Carver-Piedmont Agricultural Institute - Facility assessment, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Child Access Prevention / Safe Storage Laws - Options for Virginia, undated. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Citizens' Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion, 2014. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Reform, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Education, State Board of - Reforms, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Education Law Center - Is School Funding Fair, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Essilor - Report on the State of Vision Care in the United States, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Executive Mansion - Greenhouse, undated. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - First Lady Four Year Report, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - First Lady Second Year Report, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - First Lady Policy Binder, undated. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Fishback cases: Policy Problems and Responses, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Forestry, 2014-2015. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - General Assembly - Committees, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - George Mason University - Operation Educate the Educators, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Gift Registry, 2014. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Governor's Reports, 2014-2016. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Guns, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Holidays, 2014-2015. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Center - Turnaround Arts, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - lafayette's Hermione Voyage, 2015 June 5-7. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Legislator notes, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Library of Virginia, undated. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Medicaid, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Medicaid coverage, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Medicaid expansion, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of - Accelerating Delivery System Transformation in Virginia (Governor's briefing), 2015 Oct 1. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Memo - Architecture for Administration, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Menulin Competition, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Military Spouse Recognition, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 2014-2017. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Movin' Mania, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - National Governors Association / Democratic Governors Association, 2014 Feb. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - National Governors Association, 2015 July. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - National Governors Association, 2017 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - national Governors Association - Learning Lab on Strategies to Reduce Childhood Hunger, 2017 June. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - National Governors Association - Management Seminar for Governors' Spouses, 2017 June. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - National Governors Association, 2017 July. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear Energy and Virginia, 2014 July 7. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - College of William and Mary, 2014 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 5a)
  - Photographs - Tangier Island, 2015 June. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Daisy, 2015. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - Christmas, 2015 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - Redskins Training Camp, 2016. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - Hampton Roads Coast Guard, 2016 Mar 3. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - Hilary Clinton, undated. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - No Kid Hungry, undated. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - Christmas, undated. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - Unidentified, undated. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Preservation Virginia, undated. (Box 18, Folder 15)